export const chapter = "Chapter - 5: food and Digestion";
export const noOfActivities = 3;

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 1) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Tick the correct option:",
    questions: [
        {
          question:
            "What are the five main nutrients essential for the body's health and development?",
          optionA: "Carbohydrates, Fats, Proteins, Vitamins, Minerals",
          optionB: "Sugars, Oils, Pulses, Fresh fruits, Roughage",
          optionC: "Starch, Nuts, Milk, Green vegetables, Water",
          correctAnswer: "Carbohydrates, Fats, Proteins, Vitamins, Minerals",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Which nutrient is responsible for repairing damaged cells and worn-out tissues?",
          optionA: "Carbohydrates",
          optionB: "Proteins",
          optionC: "Fats",
          correctAnswer: "Proteins",
        },
        {
          question: "What is the primary function of fats in the body?",
          optionA: "To provide energy",
          optionB: "To store energy and keep the body warm",
          optionC: "To aid digestion",
          correctAnswer: "To store energy and keep the body warm",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Which type of carbohydrate is found in fruits, milk, honey, and sugarcane?",
          optionA: "Starch",
          optionB: "Simple carbohydrate",
          optionC: "Complex carbohydrate",
          correctAnswer: "Simple carbohydrate",
        },
        {
          question: "What is the role of vitamins in the body?",
          optionA: "To provide energy",
          optionB: "To help in digestion",
          optionC:
            "To fight against diseases, support body functions, and stay healthy",
          correctAnswer:
            "To fight against diseases, support body functions, and stay healthy",
        },
        {
          question: "Which organs are part of the digestive system?",
          optionA: "Liver, Lungs, Kidneys",
          optionB:
            "Mouth, Food Pipe, Stomach, Small Intestine, Large Intestine, Anus",
          optionC: "Heart, Brain, Pancreas",
          correctAnswer:
            "Mouth, Food Pipe, Stomach, Small Intestine, Large Intestine, Anus",
        },
        {
          question: "What is roughage, and what is its primary function?",
          optionA: "Nutrient that provides energy",
          optionB: "Fibrous part of food aiding in digestion and waste removal",
          optionC: "Component found in oils and nuts",
          correctAnswer:
            "Fibrous part of food aiding in digestion and waste removal",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Which nutrient adds bulk to our food but does not contain any nutrients itself?",
          optionA: "Proteins",
          optionB: "Carbohydrates",
          optionC: "Roughage",
          correctAnswer: "Roughage",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Approximately, what percentage of our body is made of water?",
          optionA: "40%",
          optionB: "60%",
          optionC: "80%",
          correctAnswer: "60%",
        },
        {
          question:
            "What is the process of breaking down food into simpler forms called?",
          optionA: "Absorption",
          optionB: "Digestion",
          optionC: "Assimilation",
          correctAnswer: "Digestion",
        },
      ],
  };
}

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 2) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Fill in the blank with correct option:",
    questions: [
        {
          question: "Carbohydrates are of two typesâ€”_____ and starch.",
          optionA: "Sugar",
          optionB: "Fats",
          optionC: "Proteins",
          correctAnswer: "Sugar",
        },
        {
          question: "Fats give more energy than _____ or sugar.",
          optionA: "Carbohydrates",
          optionB: "Proteins",
          optionC: "Vitamins",
          correctAnswer: "Carbohydrates",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Proteins help in the growth by repairing damaged cells and _____ tissues.",
          optionA: "Starch",
          optionB: "Roughage",
          optionC: "Worn-out",
          correctAnswer: "Worn-out",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Vitamins are essential for fighting against diseases, supporting body functions, and staying _____.",
          optionA: "Active",
          optionB: "Healthy",
          optionC: "Energetic",
          correctAnswer: "Healthy",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Minerals help in the formation of _____, teeth, and blood.",
          optionA: "Muscles",
          optionB: "Bones",
          optionC: "Skin",
          correctAnswer: "Bones",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Roughage is the fibrous part of the food that adds bulk to our food and aids in _____.",
          optionA: "Absorption",
          optionB: "Digestion",
          optionC: "Assimilation",
          correctAnswer: "Digestion",
        },
        {
          question: "Approximately, _____% of our body is made of water.",
          optionA: "40%",
          optionB: "60%",
          optionC: "80%",
          correctAnswer: "60%",
        },
        {
          question:
            "The process of breaking down food into simpler forms is called _____.",
          optionA: "Absorption",
          optionB: "Digestion",
          optionC: "Assimilation",
          correctAnswer: "Digestion",
        },
        {
          question:
            "The digestive system consists of the mouth, food pipe, stomach, small intestine, large intestine, and _____.",
          optionA: "Liver",
          optionB: "Kidneys",
          optionC: "Anus",
          correctAnswer: "Anus",
        },
        {
          question:
            "The waste formed by the large intestine is removed from the body through the _____.",
          optionA: "Nose",
          optionB: "Mouth",
          optionC: "Anus",
          correctAnswer: "Anus",
        },
      ],
  };
}

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 3) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Write 'True' for True and 'False' for False statements:",
    questions: [
        {
          question:
            "Carbohydrates are primarily found in oils, ghee, nuts, and butter.",
          optionA: "True",
          optionB: "False",
          correctAnswer: "False",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Fats play a role in storing energy and helping to keep the body warm.",
          optionA: "True",
          optionB: "False",
          correctAnswer: "True",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Proteins aid in the growth of the body by repairing damaged cells and worn-out tissues.",
          optionA: "True",
          optionB: "False",
          correctAnswer: "True",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Vitamins are primarily responsible for providing energy to the body.",
          optionA: "True",
          optionB: "False",
          correctAnswer: "False",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Minerals help in the formation of bones, teeth, and blood.",
          optionA: "True",
          optionB: "False",
          correctAnswer: "True",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Roughage, the fibrous part of food, adds bulk to the diet but does not contain any nutrients.",
          optionA: "True",
          optionB: "False",
          correctAnswer: "True",
        },
        {
          question: "Approximately 50% of our body is made of water.",
          optionA: "True",
          optionB: "False",
          correctAnswer: "False",
        },
        {
          question:
            "The process of breaking down food into simpler forms is called assimilation.",
          optionA: "True",
          optionB: "False",
          correctAnswer: "False",
        },
        {
          question:
            "The digestive system includes the mouth, food pipe, stomach, small intestine, large intestine, and anus.",
          optionA: "True",
          optionB: "False",
          correctAnswer: "True",
        },
        {
          question:
            "The Western Ghats and Eastern Ghats border the Peninsular Plateau to the west and east, respectively.",
          optionA: "True",
          optionB: "False",
          correctAnswer: "True",
        },
      ],
  };
}

export var activityData;
